hapag-lloyd.com 2015-09-07

# 1. Privacy Statement - Hapag-Lloyd

At Hapag-Lloyd, we take your privacy seriously. We follow a strict data protection policy designed to safeguard your privacy because we know that you rely on us to act responsibly with the personal information you disclose to us. You can visit our website at any time and view non-secure areas without disclosing any personal information. In these cases, the only information we store is the IP address your computer sends us plus related information. Read on to find out more about our privacy policy.

## 2\. What sorts of information does Hapag-Lloyd collect? How does it use this information?

In some cases we will ask you to voluntarily disclose personal information. Usually, this happens when you request information relating to our company. If you instruct us not to use your personal information for the purpose of contacting you, we will respect your wishes and remove your details from our filing system (this is your right of objection/ Widerspruchsrecht). You can exercise your right of objection by email or letter to the address given under “Hapag-Lloyd” in the webpage footer or to the e-mail address below.

This website uses etracker technology ([www.etracker.com](http://www.etracker.com/)) to collect data on visitor behavior. The data is collected anonymously for use in marketing and optimization. All visitor data is saved using an pseudonymous user ID and can be used to aggregate a usage profile. Cookies may be used for this purpose. The data collected by the etracker technology will not be used to determine the personal identity of a website visitor, and will not be compiled with personal data relating to the person referred to by the pseudonym, unless agreed to separately by the person concerned. 

## 3\. How do cookies work?

Cookies are small text files that are stored in the visitor’s local browser cache. It is possible to use these cookies to recognize a visitor’s browser.

Hapag-Lloyd uses session cookies to facilitate fast, secure communication while you are on our website. If you prevent us from sending session cookies to you, you may be refused access to our website or be prevented from accessing certain pages or services. The session cookies we send are automatically deleted when you close your browser. 

Hapag-Lloyd uses permanent cookies to enable our systems to identify your browser in order to offer services like your personal Online Business start page. These permanent cookies are saved on your computer and are not automatically deleted. We therefore recommend to completely log off if you share a computer with other users and allow cookies.

You can avoid the use of cookies by setting the appropriate setups of your web browser. The help function of most web browsers explain how to setup your browser to accept or refuse cookies and how to delete existing cookies.

Our website may contain links to third-party web pages that use cookie technology. Obviously, we have no access to or control over these third-party cookies.

## 4\. Does Hapag-Lloyd AG pass the information it collects on to third parties?

In certain circumstances, Hapag-Lloyd AG stores personal information (see paragraph 2). Because Hapag-Lloyd AG is part of a global group of affiliated companies, it sometimes passes on the data it collects to other members of the group at various locations around the world. 

## 5\. Our e-mail policy

If you disclose your contact details to us, we may contact you via email if this is necessary for our customer services or in order to provide you with information that you have requested. 

## 6\. Your consent

By using our website, you give your permission to Hapag-Lloyd for collecting and using the personal information described above

Please be aware that if you access our website from within the European Union, any personal data you disclose can be used for the above-described purposes outside the European Union as well as inside it. By using this website and disclosing to us your personal information, you give your permission for your personal information to be transmitted in this way.

The permission may be revoked at any time with respect to future services by sending an email to:
